<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<root>
    <head>
        <introduction> Fort Presque Isle (also Fort de la Presqu'île) was a fort built by French
            soldiers in <date year="1753">summer 1753</date> along Presque Isle Bay at present-day Erie, Pennsylvania, to
            protect the northern terminus of the Venango Path. It was the first of the French posts
            built in the <place placeType="region">Ohio Country</place>, and was part of a line that included <place
                placeType="fort">Fort Le Boeuf</place>, <place placeType="fort"> Fort
                Machault</place>, and <place placeType="fort">Fort Duquesne</place>. </introduction>
    </head>
    <body>
        <history> The fort was built as part of the French military occupation of the <place
                placeType="region">Ohio Country</place>; rival claims to the area by the British led
            to the French and Indian War. After the <date year="1759">,1759</date> British victory
            at the Battle of <place placeType="fort">Fort Niagara</place>, the French burned the
            fort and retreated from the area. The British built a new <place placeType="fort">Fort
                Presque Isle</place>, which was captured by American Indians during Pontiac's
            Rebellion. On <date month='June' day='19' year="1763">June 19, 1763</date>, the fort was surrounded by about 250 <people
                peopleType="Indians">Ottawas, Ojibwas, Wyandots, and Senecas</people>. After holding
            out for two days, the garrison of approximately sixty men surrendered on the condition
            that they could return to <place placeType="fort">Fort Pitt</place>. Most were instead
            killed after emerging from the fort The <people peopleType="British">British</people>
            built a new Fort Presque Isle, which was captured by American Indians during Pontiac's
            Rebellion. On June 19, 1763, the fort was surrounded by about 250 <people
                peopleType="Indians">Ottawas, Ojibwas, Wyandots, and Senecas</people>. After holding
            out for two days, the garrison of approximately sixty men surrendered on the condition
            that they could return to <place placeType="fort">Fort Pitt</place>. Most were instead
            killed after emerging from the fort. General Anthony Wayne first arrived in the area of
            Presque Isle in 1786. In 1795, 200 Federal troops from <person rank="General"
                last="Wayne" first="Anthony">Wayne's </person>army, under the direction of <person
                rank="Captain" last="Grubb" first="John">Captain John Grubb</person>, built a
            blockhouse on Garrison Hill, in present-day <place placeType="city">Erie</place>, <place
                placeType="state">Pennsylvania</place>. Also named <place placeType="fort">Fort
                Presque Isle</place>, the blockhouse was used as part of a defense against Native
            American uprisings. It was also used during the War of 1812. <person rank="General"
                first="Anthony" last="Wayne">General Wayne </person>was stricken ill at Fort Presque
            Isle and died there in 1796. At his request, his body was buried under the flagpole of
            the northwest blockhouse of the fort. This blockhouse burned in 1852. In 1880, the
            Commonwealth of <place placeType="state">Pennsylvania</place> reconstructed the blockhouse at Second and Ash Streets,
                <place placeType="city">Erie</place>, as a memorial to <person rank="General" first="Anthony" last="Wayne"></person>General Wayne. The
            Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission has recognized the reconstructed
            blockhouse as eligible for placement on the National Register of Historic Places. The
            blockhouse is located at N 42° 08.400, W 80° 04.463. .</history>
    </body>
</root>
