<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<text> Taken from: Wikipedia <div>
        <introduction>><place placeType="fort">Fort Le Boeuf</place> (often referred to as Fort de
            la Rivière au Bœuf) was a fort established by the French during <date year="1753"
                >1753</date> on a fork of French Creek (in the drainage area of the River Ohio), in
            present-day <place placeType="city">Waterford</place>, in northwest Pennsylvania. The
            fort was part of a line that included <place placeType="fort">Fort Presque Isle,</place>
            <place>Fort Machault</place>, and <place placeType="fort"/>Fort Duquesne. The fort was
            located about 15 miles (24 km) from the shores of<place placeType="lake"> Lake
                Erie</place>, on the banks of LeBoeuf Creek, for which the fort was named. The
            French portaged supplies and trade goods from Lake Erie overland to<place
                placeType="fort"> Fort Le Boeuf</place>. From there they traveled by raft and canoe
            down French Creek to the rivers Allegheny, Ohio and Mississippi. Today, the site of the
            fort is occupied by the Fort LeBoeuf Museum, operated by the Fort LeBoeuf Historical
            Society.</introduction>
    </div>
    <div>
        <history>History <perosn rank="Captain" first="Paul" last="Marin de la Malgue">Captain Paul
                Marin de la Malgue</perosn> began construction on <date month="July" day="11"
                year="1753">11 July 1753</date>; Jacques Legardeur de Saint-Pierre began command of
            the fort on<date month="December" day="3" year="1753"> 3 December 1753</date>. This fort
            was the second of a series of posts that the <people peopleType="French">French</people>
            built between spring 1753 and summer 1754 to assert their possession of the Ohio
            Country. These four posts <place placeType="fort">Fort Presque Isle</place>,<place
                placeType="fort"> Fort LeBoeuf</place>, <place placeType="fort">Fort
                Machault</place>, and <place placeType="fort">Fort Duquesne</place> ran from Lake
            Erie to the Forks of the Ohio; they represented the last links of France's effort to
            connect its dominions in Canada with those in the Illinois Country and <place
                placeType="colony">Louisiana</place>. The English trading post of John Frazier, at
            Venango at the junction of <place placeType="creek">French Creek</place> and the <place
                placeType="river">Allegheny River</place>(where Franklin is now located) was seized
            and occupied. Leaving a force to garrison the new posts, the French command returned to
            Canada for the winter.[2] <place placeType="fort">Fort LeBoeuf </place>(modern
            Waterford, Pennsylvania) guarded the southern end of the portage road between Lake Erie
            and French Creek, which flowed to the <place placeType="river">Allegheny River</place>
            and ultimately to the River Ohio. It served as a French trading post and garrison until
            1759, when the capture of Fort Niagara forced the French to abandon the <place
                placeType="region">Ohio Country</place>. </history>
    </div>
    <Washington> Washington's mission: <person last="Dinwiddie" first="Robert">Robert
            Dinwiddie</person>, <person first="Robert" last="Dinwiddie">the governor of
            Virginia</person>, sent the 21-year-old George Washington to<place placeType="fort">
            Fort Le Boeuf</place> with seven escorts, in order to deliver a message to the French
        demanding that they leave the Ohio Country. <person rank="Governor" last="Dinwiddie"
            first="Robert">Dinwiddie's</person> initiative was in response to the French building
        forts in the Ohio Country. Washington took Christopher Gist along as his guide; during the
        trip, Gist saved the young Washington's life on two separate occasions. <person
            last="Washington" first="George">Washington</person> and Gist arrived at<place
            placeType="fort"> Fort Le Boeuf</place> on <date month="December" day="11" year="1753"
            >11 December 1753</date>. Jacques Legardeur de Saint-Pierre, commandant at <place
            placeType="fort">Fort Le Boeuf</place>, a tough veteran of the west, received Washington
        politely, but contemptuously rejected his blustering ultimatum. French Forts, 1753 and 1754
        Jacques Legardeur de Saint-Pierre gave Washington three days hospitality at the fort, and
        then gave Washington a letter for him to deliver to Dinwiddie. The letter ordered the
        Governor of Virginia to deliver his demand to the Major General of New France in the
        capital, <place placeType="city">Quebec City</place>. During his stay,<person rank="Major"
            Last="Washington" first="George"> Washington</person> noted that the fort had one
        hundred men, a large number of officers, 50 birch canoes and 70 pine canoes, many
        unfinished. He described the fort as on a south or west fork of French creek, near the
        water, and almost surrounded by it. Four houses composed the sides. The bastions were made
        of piles driven into the ground, standing more than 12 feet (3.7 m) high, and sharpened at
        the top. Port holes for cannon and loop-holes for small-arms were cut into the bastions.
        Each bastion mounted eight six-pound cannon and one four-pound cannon guarded the gate.
        Inside the bastions stood a guard-house, chapel, doctor's lodging and the commander's
        private stores. Outside the fort were several log barracks, some covered with bark, others
        with boards. In addition, there were stables, a smithy and other buildings. </Washington>
    <div> </div>
</text>
