<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<root>
    <head>
        <introduction> Fort Presque Isle (also Fort de la Presqu'île) was a fort built by French
            soldiers in summer 1753 along Presque Isle Bay at present-day Erie, Pennsylvania, to
            protect the northern terminus of the Venango Path. It was the first of the French posts
            built in the Ohio Country, [1] and was part of a line that included <place
                placeType="fort">Fort Le Boeuf</place>, <place placeType="fort"> Fort
                Machault</place>, and <place placeType="fort">Fort Duquesne</place>. </introduction>
    </head>
    <body>
        <history> The fort was built as part of the French military occupation of the Ohio Country;
            rival claims to the area by the British led to the French and Indian War. After the
                <date year="1759">,1759</date> British victory at the Battle of Fort Niagara, the
            French burned the fort and retreated from the area. The British built a new Fort Presque
            Isle, which was captured by American Indians during Pontiac's Rebellion. On June 19,
            1763, the fort was surrounded by about 250 Ottawas, Ojibwas, Wyandots, and Senecas.
            After holding out for two days, the garrison of approximately sixty men surrendered on
            the condition that they could return to <place placeType="fort">Fort Pitt</place>. Most
            were instead killed after emerging from the fort The <people peopleType="British"
                >British</people> built a new Fort Presque Isle, which was captured by American
            Indians during Pontiac's Rebellion. On June 19, 1763, the fort was surrounded by about
            250 Ottawas, Ojibwas, Wyandots, and Senecas. After holding out for two days, the
            garrison of approximately sixty men surrendered on the condition that they could return
            to Fort Pitt. Most were instead killed after emerging from the fort. General Anthony
            Wayne first arrived in the area of Presque Isle in 1786. In 1795, 200 Federal troops
            from <person rank="General" last="Wayne" first="Anthony">Wayne's </person>army, under
            the direction of <person rank="Captain" last="Grubb" fist="John">Captain John
                Grubb</person>, built a blockhouse on Garrison Hill, in present-day <place
                placeType="city">Erie</place>, <place placeType="state">Pennsylvania</place>. Also
            named <place placeType="fort">Fort Presque Isle</place>, the blockhouse was used as part
            of a defense against Native American uprisings. It was also used during the War of 1812.
            General Wayne was stricken ill at Fort Presque Isle and died there in 1796. At his
            request, his body was buried under the flagpole of the northwest blockhouse of the fort.
            This blockhouse burned in 1852. In 1880, the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania reconstructed
            the blockhouse at Second and Ash Streets, Erie, as a memorial to General Wayne. The
            Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission has recognized the reconstructed
            blockhouse as eligible for placement on the National Register of Historic Places. The
            blockhouse is located at N 42° 08.400, W 80° 04.463. .</history>
    </body>
</root>
