<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<text> NOTE:Taken from Wikipedia <div>
        <heading> Fort Machault was a fort built by the French in 1754 near the confluence of<place
                placeType="river"> French Creek</place> with the <place placeType="river">Allegheny
                River</place>, at present-day <place placeType="city">Franklin</place>, in northwest
            Pennsylvania. The fort was part of a line that included <place placeType="fort">Fort
                Presque Isle</place>, <place placeType="fort">Fort Le Boeuf</place>, and <place
                placeType="fort">Fort Duquesne</place>. </heading>
    </div>
    <div>
        <description>
            <p> The fort was built on a hill, 60 yards west of the <place placeType="river"
                />Allegheny River. The fort was in the form of a parallelogram, about 75 by 105 feet
                (32 m). The curtain was made of hewed timber, stacked lengthwise. The four corners
                had bastions in the form of polygons. The bastions were built of saplings, eight
                inches (203 mm) thick, and 13 feet (4.0 m) in height. The gate fronted the river.
                Inside the fort were a magazine, several officer's barracks, with two stories and
                stone chimneys. The <people peopleType="soldiers"/>soldiers barracks consisted of 45
                buildings outside the fort. </p>
        </description>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p>In <date year="1753">1753</date>, <person rank="Governor" first="Jean" last="de Lauson"
                >Governor Jean de Lauson</person> sought to build a fortified trading post at the
            confluence of the Allegheny River and French Creek at Venango. That year, the English
            traders were expelled from Venango and Captain Philippe-Thomas Chabert de Joncaire
            established Fort d'Anjou with a permanent garrison at the location. </p>
        <p> In December 1753, <person rank="Major" last="Washington" first="George">George
                Washington</person> used the Venango Path to reach Fort Machault during his first
            expedition into the Ohio Country. <person rank="Major" last="Washington" first="George"
                >Washington</person>, with an escort of seven men and a letter from <person
                rank="Governor" last="Dinwiddie" first="Rovert">Governor Robert Dinwiddie</person>
            of <place placeType="colony">Virginia</place>, protesting the <people
                peopleType="French">French</people> invasion of lands claimed by Great Britain and
            demanding their immediate withdrawal.[2] The French officer at the fort said he did not
            have the power to negotiate with the British. Therefore, he told Washington to go to
            Fort Le Boeuf instead to meet with a higher-ranking officer. The French and Indian War
            began on <date month="May" day="28" year="1754">May 28, 1754</date> with the Battle of
            Jumonville Glen. </p>
        <p>
            <person>Captain Philippe-Thomas Chabert de Joncaire</person> finished building Fort
            d'Anjou Fort Machault in <date month="April" year="1754">April 1754</date>. It was named
            in honor of prominent financier, Jean-Baptiste Machault d'Arnouville, the French
            Minister of the Marine at the time of its construction. It was also known as "Venango,"
            the name of the nearby Delaware Indian village. Captain Philippe-Thomas Chabert de
            Joncaire was replaced by Michel Maray de La Chauvignerie as the officer in charge of
            constructing the fort in <date year="1754">1754</date>, which eventually became Fort
            Machault. La Chauvignerie's construction efforts were set back by shortages of manpower
            and wood, resulting in sporadic construction and improvements until November 1758 when
            he was replaced by François-Marie Le Marchand de Lignery. </p>
        <p> One of four forts built by the French and Canadiens, to control the Venango Path between
            Lake Erie and the Ohio River, <place placeType="fort">Fort Machault</place> was located
            in modern <place placeType="city">Franklin</place>, <place placeType="state"
                >Pennsylvania</place>, at the confluence of French Creek and the Allegheny River.
            Fort Machault was the last stop on the supply route from Canada to Fort Duquesne. Prior
            to the arrival of the French in <date year="1753">1753</date>, Pennsylvania blacksmith
            and Indian trader <person last="Fraser" first="John">John Fraser</person> had set up
            shop on this site, supplying Indians in the region with trade goods and repairing their
            guns and other metal wares. His business was an example of the western expansion of
            Pennsylvania's fur trade that prompted the French to fortify the <place
                placeType="region">Ohio Country</place>, for fear of losing trade and influence
            among the Indians there. </p><p> In 1756, William Johnson, who had escaped from Native
            Americans, described the fort as a "Captain's command of about 50 men; the Fort of
            Stockades, very weak, and scarce of provisions . . . " In 1758, Colonel Mercer, in a
            report from <place placeType="fort">Fort Pitt</place>, reported that there were about
            100 soldiers at Fort Machault, where the French had 11 flat-bottomed boats called
            "batteaus" and a large gun the size of a quart pot "which they fire off by a train of
            powder." </p>
        <p> After abandoning<place placeType="fort"> Fort Duquesne </place>in November 1758, the
            French fell back to Fort Machault, and the British expected them to launch a
            counterattack from there in the following campaign season. In July 1759, the French
            began a campaign to capture <place placeType="fort">Fort Pitt</place>. Nearly a thousand
            French and Canadiens and a thousand Native Americans mustered at Fort Machault. The
            British, however, began a siege of Fort Niagara. The fall of Fort Niagara in summer
            1759, however, made the French presence in the Ohio Country untenable. The assault on
            Fort Pitt was abandoned, and available forces were sent to relieve Fort Niagara. </p>
        <p> On July 25, 1759, the French surrendered Fort Niagara. In August 1759, the commander of
            Fort Presque Isle sent word to Fort Le Boeuf and Fort Machault to abandon their forts.
            The French burned Fort Machault to the ground and retreated to Canada in anticipation of
            a British expedition north from the Forks of the Ohio. In 1760, the British built Fort
            Venango near this site </p>
    </div>
</text>
