<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<root>


    <head>
        <intro>George Washington The Journal of Major George Washington (1754)</intro>

        <p n="1">In October of 1753, George Washington, a 21-year-old major in the Virginia militia,
            volunteered to carry a letter from the governor of Virginia to the French commander of
            the forts recently built on the headwaters of the Ohio River in northwestern
            Pennsylvania. The French had recently expanded their military operations from the Great
            Lakes into the Ohio country, and had spent the summer of 1753 building forts and roads
            along the Allegheny River, with the design of linking their trade routes and sphere of
            influence down the Ohio to the Mississippi. Virginia governor Robert Dinwiddie believed
            them to be in violation of treaties and claims that made those territories part of
            Virginia and Pennsylvania, as granted by the British Crown, and his letter to the French
            commander instructed him to cease, desist, and depart from those regions. </p>
        <p n="2"> Washington left Williamsburg, Virginia on October 31, 1753, and completed the
            round trip of more than 1,000 miles by horse, foot, canoe, and raft in about ten weeks.
            He was accompanied by Christopher Gist, an explorer and surveyor employed by the Ohio
            Company, by Jacob Van Braam, a French Interpreter, four Indian traders and baggage-men,
            and various Indian delegations and guards, including Tanacharison, known as the
            “Half-King.” Washington accomplished far more than the mere delivery of a letter: he
            practiced diplomacy to keep the Native leaders allied to the English cause; he
            interviewed French deserters and reported P on the extent of French military posts
            between New Orleans and the Great Lakes; he reconnoitered the Forks of the Ohio with an
            eye to the proper site for building a fort; and he inspected and reported on the
            construction of the new French forts and made estimates of their strength and
            preparations for the following year’s expeditions.</p>
        <p n="3">When Washington arrived back in Williamsburg on January 16, 1754, Governor
            Dinwiddie immediately asked him to prepare a written report for the House of Burgesses.
            Dinwiddie then had this eport printed, and it became very popular reading. The Virginia
            legislature was so pleased with his mission and his report that they voted him a £50
            reward. The Journal of Major George Washington was reprinted in various colonial
            newspapers as far away as Boston, and a British edition was issued in London later that
            same year, for which Washington sent materials for the preparation of a map.</p>
        <p n="4"> This online electronic text edition of the Journal is based on the first American
            edition published at Williamsburg in February 1754. It includes some annotations for the
            nonspecialist reader and a note on the text discussing the sources and the few
            emendations made. </p>

        <p n="5">It is accompanied by 2 maps, attached as supplementary PDF files: one is a copy of
            the map that appeared with the London edition, showing the whole region from the
            Atlantic to the Mississippi, based on materials furnished by Washington; the other is a
            detail derived from the map accompanying Thomas Jefferson’s Notes on the State of
            Virginia (1787), showing the frontier region through which Washington travelled, between
            Cumberland (Md.) and Lake Erie. Of the two, the Jefferson map shows the geography with
            somewhat greater accuracy. </p>
    </head>

    <body>
        <title>THE JOURNAL OF Major George Washington, SENT BY THE Hon.ROBERT DINWIDDIE,Esq; His
            Majesty’s Lieutenant-Governor, and Commander in Chief of VIRGINIA, TO THE COMMANDANT OF
            THE FRENCH FORCES ON O H I O. TO WHICH ARE ADDED, THE GOVERNOR’s LETTER, AND A
            TRANSLATION OF THE FRENCH OFFICER’S ANSWER. WILLIAMSBURG: Printed by WILLIAM HUNTER.
            1754.</title>
        <p n="6">I was commissioned and appointed by the Honourable Robert Dinwiddie, Esq;
            Governor,&c. of Virginia, to visit and deliver a Letter to the Commandant of the French
            Forces on the Ohio, and set out on the in- tended Journey the same Day; the next,
            Iarrived at Fredericksburg, and engaged Mr. Jacob Vanbraam, to be my French Interpreter;
            and proceeded with him to Alex- andria, where we provided Necessaries ; from thence we
            went to Winchester, and got Baggage, Horses, &c. and from thence we pursued the new Road
            to Wills-Creek, where we arrived the 14th of November.</p>


        <p>Here I engaged Mr. Gist to pilot us out, and also hired four others as Servitors, Barnaby
            Currin, and John MacQuire, In- dian Traders, Henry Steward, and William Jenkins, and in
            Company with those Persons, left the Inhabitants the Day following.</p>
        <p>The excessive Rains and vast Quantity of Snow that had fallen, prevented our reaching Mr.
            Frazier’s an Indian Trader, at the Mouth of Turtle-Creek, on Monongahela, till Thursday
            the 22d. We were informed here, that Expresses were sent a few Days ago to the Traders
            down the River, to acquaint them with the French General’s Death, and the Return of the
            major Part of the French Army into Winter Quarters.</p>
        <p> The Waters were quite impassable, without swimming our Horses; which obliged us to get
            the Loan of a Canoe from Frazier, and to send Barnaby Currin, and Henry Steward, down
            Monongahela, with our Baggage, to meet us at the Forks of Ohio, about 10 Miles, to cross
            Aligany. </p>
        <p> As I got down before the Canoe, I spent some Time in view- ing the Rivers, and the Land
            in the Fork, which I think ex- tremely well situated for a Fort, as it has the absolut
            Com- mand of both Rivers. The Land at the Point is 20 or 25 Feet above the common
            Surface of the Water, and a considerable Bottom of flat, well-timbered Land all around
            it, very conve- nient for Building : The Rivers are each a Quarter of a Mile, or more,
            across, and run here very near at right Angles : Alig- any bearing N. E. and Monongahela
            S. E. the former of these two is a very rapid and swift running Water, the other deep
            and still, without any perceptible Fall. </p>
        <p> About two Miles from this, on the South East Side of the River, at the Place where the
            Ohio Company intended to erect a Fort, lives Shingiss, king of the Delawares; we call’d
            upon him, to invite him to Council at the Loggs-Town. </p>
        <p> As I had taken a good deal of Notice Yesterday of the Situ- ation at the Forks, my
            Curiosity led me to examine this more particularly, and I think it greatly inferior,
            either for Defence or Advantages ; especially the latter ; for a Fort at the Forks would
            be equally well situated on Ohio, and have the entire Command of Monongahela, which runs
            up to our Settlements and is extremely well design’d for Water Carriage, as it is of a
            deep still Nature ; besides, a Fort at the Fork might be built at a much less Expence,
            than at the other Place.——— </p>
        <p> Nature has well contrived the lower Place, for Water Defence; but the Hill whereon it
            must stand being about a Quarter of a Mile in Length, and then descending gradually on
            the Land Side, will render it difficult and very expensive, making a sufficient
            Fortification there.—The whole Flat upon the Hill must be taken in, or the Side next the
            Descent made extremely high ; or else the Hill cut away : Otherwise, the En- emy may
            raise Batteries within that Distance without being expos’d to a single Shot from the
            Fort. </p>
        <p> Shingiss attended us to the Loggs-Town, where we arrived between Sun-setting and Dark,
            the 25th Day after I left Wil- liamsburg: We travelled over some extreme good, and bad
            Land, to get to this Place. — </p>
        <p> As soon as I came into Town, I went to Monacatoocha (as the Half-King was out at his
            hunting-Cabbin on little Beaver Creek, about 15 Miles off ) and inform’d him by John
            Davi- son my Indian Interpreter, that I was sent a Messenger to the French General; and
            was ordered to call upon the Sachems of the Six Nations, to acquaint them with it.—I
            gave him a String of Wampum, and a Twist of Tobacco, and desired him to send for the
            Half-King ; which he promised to do by a Run- ner in the Morning, and for other
            Sachems.—I invited him and the other great Men present to my Tent, where they stay’d
            about an Hour and return’d. </p>
        <p> According to the best Observations I could make, Mr. Gist’s new Settlement (which we
            pass’d by) bears about W. N. W. 70 Miles from Wills-Creek ; Shanapins, or the Forks N.
            by W. or N. N. W. about 50 Miles from that ; and from thence to the Loggs-Town, the
            Course is nearly West about 18 or 20 Miles ; so that the whole Distance, as we went and
            computed it, is at least 135 or 140 Miles from our back Inhabitants. </p>

        <p> 25th, Came to Town four of ten Frenchmen that deserted from a Company at the Cuscuscas,
            which lies at the Mouth of this River ; I got the following Account from them. They were
            sent from New Orleans with 100 Men, and 8 Canoe Loads of Provisions to this Place ;
            where they expected to have met the same Number of Men, from the Forts this Side Lake
            Erie, to convey them and the Stores up, who were not arrived when they ran off. </p>

        <p> I enquired into the Situation of the French, on the Missi- sippi, their Number, and what
            Forts they had built: They inform’d me, That there were four small Forts between New-
            Orleans and the Black-Islands, garrison’d with about 30 or 40 Men, and a few small
            Pieces, in each : That at New-Orleans, which is near the Mouth of the Missisippi, there
            are 35 Com- panies, of 40 Men each, with a pretty strong Fort mount- ing 8 Carriage
            Guns; and at the Black-Islands there are sev- eral Companies, and a Fort with 6 Guns.
            The Black-Islands are about 130 Leagues above the Mouth of the Ohio, which is about 350
            above New-Orleans : They also acquainted me, that there was a small pallisado’d Fort on
            the Ohio, at the Mouth of the Obaish about 60 Leagues from the Missisippi: The Obaish
            heads near the West End of Lake Erie, and affords the Communication between the French
            on Missisippi and those on the Lakes. These Deserters came up from the lower Shanoah
            Town with one Brown, an Indian Trader, and were going to Philadelphia. </p>

        <p> About 3 o’Clock this Evening the Half-King came to Town ; I went up and invited him and
            Davison, privately, to my Tent, and desir’d him to relate some of the Particulars of his
            Journey to the French Commandant, and Reception there ; and to give me an Account of the
            Ways and Distance. He told me, that the nearest and levellest Way was now impassable, by
            Reason of many large miry Savannas; that we must be obliged to go by Venango, and should
            not get to the near Fort under 5 or 6 Night’s Sleep, good Travelling. When he went to
            the Fort, he said he was received in a very stern Manner by the late Com- mander; Who
            ask’d him very abruptly, what he had come about, and to declare his Business, which he
            said he did in the following Speech. </p>
        <p> Fathers, I am come to tell you your own Speeches; what your own Mouths have declared.
            Fathers, You, in former Days, set a Silver Bason before us, wherein there was the Leg of
            a Beaver, and desir’d of all Nations to come and eat of it ; to eat in Peace and Plenty,
            and not to be churlish to one another ; and that if any such Person should be found to
            be a Disturber, I here lay down by the Edge of the Dish a Rod, which you must scourge
            them with ; and if I your Father, should get foolish, in my old Days, I desire you may
            use it upon me as well as others. </p>
        <p> Now Fathers, it is you that are the Disturbers in this Land, by coming and building your
            Towns, and taking it away unknown to us, and by Force. </p>
        <p> Fathers, We kindled a Fire a long Time ago, at a Place called Montreal, where we desired
            you to stay, and not to come and in- trude upon our Land. I now desire you may dispatch
            to that Place ; for be it known to you, Fathers, that this is our Land, and not yours </p>
        <p> Fathers, I desire you may hear me in Civilness ; if not, we must handle that Rod which
            was laid down for the Use of the obstreper- ous. If you had come in a peaceable Manner,
            like our Brothers the English, we should not have been against your trading with us, as
            they do ; but to come, Fathers, and build great Houses upon our Land, and to take it by
            Force, is what we cannot submit to. </p>
        <p> Fathers, Both you and the English are white, we live in a Country between; therefore the
            Land belongs to neither one nor t’other : But the Great Being above allow’d it to be a
            Place of Res- idence for us ; so Fathers, I desire you to withdraw, as I have done our
            Brothers the English ; for I will keep you at Arms length : I lay this down as a Trial
            for both, to see which will have the great- est Regard to it, and that Side we will
            stand by, and make equal Sharers with us. Our Brothers the English have heard this, and
            I come now to tell it to you, for I am not afraid to discharge you off this Land. </p>
        <p> This he said was the Substance of what he said to the Gen- eral, who made this Reply. 15
            Miles asunder, and a large Waggon Road between ; they are both built after the same
            Model, but different in the Size ; that on the Lake the largest; he gave me a Plan of
            them, of his own drawing. Now my Child, I have heard your Speech, you spoke first, but
            it is my Time to speak now. Where is my Wampum that you took away, with the Marks of
            Towns in it? This Wampum I do not know, which you have discharged me off the Land with ;
            but you need not put yourself to the Trouble of speaking, for I will not hear you : I am
            not afraid of Flies, or Musquitos, for Indians are such as those; I tell you, down that
            River I will go, and will build upon it, according to my Command : If the River was
            block’d up, I have Forces sufficient to burst it open, and tread under my Feet all that
            stand in Opposition, together with their Alliances ; for my Force is as the Sand upon
            the Sea Shore: Therefore, here is your Wampum, I fling it at you. Child, you talk
            foolish; you say this Land belongs to you, but there is not the Black of my Nail yours :
            I saw that Land sooner than you did, before the Shannoahs and you were at War : Lead was
            the Man that went down, and took Pos- session of that River : It is my Land, and I will
            have it, let who will stand up for, or say against it. I’ll buy and sell with the Eng-
            lish, (mockingly). If People will be rul’d by me, they may expect Kindness, but not
            else. </p>


    </body>








</root>
