<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>





<?xml-model href="Washington_Trail.css" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>

    <div>





        <head>

            <intro>George Washington The Journal of Major George Washington (1754)</intro>



            <p n="1">In October of 1753, George Washington, a 21-year-old major in the Virginia

                militia, volunteered to carry a letter from the governor of Virginia to the French

                commander of the forts recently built on the headwaters of the Ohio River in

                northwestern Pennsylvania. The French had recently expanded their military

                operations from the Great Lakes into the Ohio country, and had spent the summer of

                1753 building forts and roads along the Allegheny River, with the design of linking

                their trade routes and sphere of influence down the Ohio to the Mississippi.

                Virginia governor Robert Dinwiddie believed them to be in violation of treaties and

                claims that made those territories part of Virginia and Pennsylvania, as granted by

                the British Crown, and his letter to the French commander instructed him to cease,

                desist, and depart from those regions. </p>

            <p n="2"> Washington left Williamsburg, Virginia on October 31, 1753, and completed the

                round trip of more than 1,000 miles by horse, foot, canoe, and raft in about ten

                weeks. He was accompanied by Christopher Gist, an explorer and surveyor employed by

                the Ohio Company, by Jacob Van Braam, a French Interpreter, four Indian traders and

                baggage-men, and various Indian delegations and guards, including Tanacharison,

                known as the “Half-King.” Washington accomplished far more than the mere delivery of

                a letter: he practiced diplomacy to keep the Native leaders allied to the English

                cause; he interviewed French deserters and reported P on the extent of French

                military posts between New Orleans and the Great Lakes; he reconnoitered the Forks

                of the Ohio with an eye to the proper site for building a fort; and he inspected and

                reported on the construction of the new French forts and made estimates of their

                strength and preparations for the following year’s expeditions.</p>

            <p n="3">When Washington arrived back in Williamsburg on January 16, 1754, Governor

                Dinwiddie immediately asked him to prepare a written report for the House of

                Burgesses. Dinwiddie then had this eport printed, and it became very popular

                reading. The Virginia legislature was so pleased with his mission and his report

                that they voted him a £50 reward. The Journal of Major George Washington was

                reprinted in various colonial newspapers as far away as Boston, and a British

                edition was issued in London later that same year, for which Washington sent

                materials for the preparation of a map.</p>

            <p n="4"> This online electronic text edition of the Journal is based on the first

                American edition published at Williamsburg in February 1754. It includes some

                annotations for the nonspecialist reader and a note on the text discussing the

                sources and the few emendations made. </p>



            <p n="5">It is accompanied by 2 maps, attached as supplementary PDF files: one is a copy

                of the map that appeared with the London edition, showing the whole region from the

                Atlantic to the Mississippi, based on materials furnished by Washington; the other

                is a detail derived from the map accompanying Thomas Jefferson’s Notes on the State

                of Virginia (1787), showing the frontier region through which Washington travelled,

                between Cumberland (Md.) and Lake Erie. Of the two, the Jefferson map shows the

                geography with somewhat greater accuracy. </p>

        </head>



        <body>

            <title>THE JOURNAL OF Major George Washington, SENT BY THE Hon.ROBERT DINWIDDIE,Esq; His

                Majesty’s Lieutenant-Governor, and Commander in Chief of VIRGINIA, TO THE COMMANDANT

                OF THE FRENCH FORCES ON O H I O. TO WHICH ARE ADDED, THE GOVERNOR’s LETTER, AND A

                TRANSLATION OF THE FRENCH OFFICER’S ANSWER. WILLIAMSBURG: Printed by WILLIAM HUNTER.

                1754.</title>

            <p n="6">I was commissioned and appointed by the Honourable Robert Dinwiddie, Esq;

                Governor,&amp;c. of Virginia, to visit and deliver a Letter to the Commandant of the

                French Forces on the Ohio, and set out on the in- tended Journey the same Day; the

                next, Iarrived at Fredericksburg, and engaged Mr. Jacob Vanbraam, to be my French

                Interpreter; and proceeded with him to Alex- andria, where we provided Necessaries ;

                from thence we went to Winchester, and got Baggage, Horses, &amp;c. and from thence

                we pursued the new Road to Wills-Creek, where we arrived the 14th of November.</p>





            <p n="7">Here I engaged Mr. Gist to pilot us out, and also hired four others as

                Servitors, Barnaby Currin, and John MacQuire, In- dian Traders, Henry Steward, and

                William Jenkins, and in Company with those Persons, left the Inhabitants the Day

                following.</p>

            <p n="8">The excessive Rains and vast Quantity of Snow that had fallen, prevented our

                reaching Mr. Frazier’s an Indian Trader, at the Mouth of Turtle-Creek, on

                Monongahela, till Thursday the 22d. We were informed here, that Expresses were sent

                a few Days ago to the Traders down the River, to acquaint them with the French

                General’s Death, and the Return of the major Part of the French Army into Winter

                Quarters.</p>

            <p n="9"> The Waters were quite impassable, without swimming our Horses; which obliged

                us to get the Loan of a Canoe from Frazier, and to send Barnaby Currin, and Henry

                Steward, down Monongahela, with our Baggage, to meet us at the Forks of Ohio, about

                10 Miles, to cross Aligany. </p>

            <p n="10"> As I got down before the Canoe, I spent some Time in view- ing the Rivers,

                and the Land in the Fork, which I think ex- tremely well situated for a Fort, as it

                has the absolut Com- mand of both Rivers. The Land at the Point is 20 or 25 Feet

                above the common Surface of the Water, and a considerable Bottom of flat,

                well-timbered Land all around it, very conve- nient for Building : The Rivers are

                each a Quarter of a Mile, or more, across, and run here very near at right Angles :

                Alig- any bearing N. E. and Monongahela S. E. the former of these two is a very

                rapid and swift running Water, the other deep and still, without any perceptible

                Fall. </p>

            <p n="11"> About two Miles from this, on the South East Side of the River, at the Place

                where the Ohio Company intended to erect a Fort, lives Shingiss, king of the

                Delawares; we call’d upon him, to invite him to Council at the Loggs-Town. </p>

            <p n="12"> As I had taken a good deal of Notice Yesterday of the Situ- ation at the

                Forks, my Curiosity led me to examine this more particularly, and I think it greatly

                inferior, either for Defence or Advantages ; especially the latter ; for a Fort at

                the Forks would be equally well situated on Ohio, and have the entire Command of

                Monongahela, which runs up to our Settlements and is extremely well design’d for

                Water Carriage, as it is of a deep still Nature ; besides, a Fort at the Fork might

                be built at a much less Expence, than at the other Place.——— </p>

            <p n="13"> Nature has well contrived the lower Place, for Water Defence; but the Hill

                whereon it must stand being about a Quarter of a Mile in Length, and then descending

                gradually on the Land Side, will render it difficult and very expensive, making a

                sufficient Fortification there.—The whole Flat upon the Hill must be taken in, or

                the Side next the Descent made extremely high ; or else the Hill cut away :

                Otherwise, the En- emy may raise Batteries within that Distance without being

                expos’d to a single Shot from the Fort. </p>

            <p n="14"> Shingiss attended us to the Loggs-Town, where we arrived between Sun-setting

                and Dark, the 25th Day after I left Wil- liamsburg: We travelled over some extreme

                good, and bad Land, to get to this Place. — </p>

            <p n="15"> As soon as I came into Town, I went to Monacatoocha (as the Half-King was out

                at his hunting-Cabbin on little Beaver Creek, about 15 Miles off ) and inform’d him

                by John Davi- son my Indian Interpreter, that I was sent a Messenger to the French

                General; and was ordered to call upon the Sachems of the Six Nations, to acquaint

                them with it.—I gave him a String of Wampum, and a Twist of Tobacco, and desired him

                to send for the Half-King ; which he promised to do by a Run- ner in the Morning,

                and for other Sachems.—I invited him and the other great Men present to my Tent,

                where they stay’d about an Hour and return’d. </p>

            <p n="16"> According to the best Observations I could make, Mr. Gist’s new Settlement

                (which we pass’d by) bears about W. N. W. 70 Miles from Wills-Creek ; Shanapins, or

                the Forks N. by W. or N. N. W. about 50 Miles from that ; and from thence to the

                Loggs-Town, the Course is nearly West about 18 or 20 Miles ; so that the whole

                Distance, as we went and computed it, is at least 135 or 140 Miles from our back

                Inhabitants. </p>



            <p n="17"> 25th, Came to Town four of ten Frenchmen that deserted from a Company at the

                Cuscuscas, which lies at the Mouth of this River ; I got the following Account from

                them. They were sent from New Orleans with 100 Men, and 8 Canoe Loads of Provisions

                to this Place ; where they expected to have met the same Number of Men, from the

                Forts this Side Lake Erie, to convey them and the Stores up, who were not arrived

                when they ran off. </p>



            <p n="18"> I enquired into the Situation of the French, on the Missi- sippi, their

                Number, and what Forts they had built: They inform’d me, That there were four small

                Forts between New- Orleans and the Black-Islands, garrison’d with about 30 or 40

                Men, and a few small Pieces, in each : That at New-Orleans, which is near the Mouth

                of the Missisippi, there are 35 Com- panies, of 40 Men each, with a pretty strong

                Fort mount- ing 8 Carriage Guns; and at the Black-Islands there are sev- eral

                Companies, and a Fort with 6 Guns. The Black-Islands are about 130 Leagues above the

                Mouth of the Ohio, which is about 350 above New-Orleans : They also acquainted me,

                that there was a small pallisado’d Fort on the Ohio, at the Mouth of the Obaish

                about 60 Leagues from the Missisippi: The Obaish heads near the West End of Lake

                Erie, and affords the Communication between the French on Missisippi and those on

                the Lakes. These Deserters came up from the lower Shanoah Town with one Brown, an

                Indian Trader, and were going to Philadelphia. </p>



            <p n="19"> About 3 o’Clock this Evening the Half-King came to Town ; I went up and

                invited him and Davison, privately, to my Tent, and desir’d him to relate some of

                the Particulars of his Journey to the French Commandant, and Reception there ; and

                to give me an Account of the Ways and Distance. He told me, that the nearest and

                levellest Way was now impassable, by Reason of many large miry Savannas; that we

                must be obliged to go by Venango, and should not get to the near Fort under 5 or 6

                Night’s Sleep, good Travelling. When he went to the Fort, he said he was received in

                a very stern Manner by the late Com- mander; Who ask’d him very abruptly, what he

                had come about, and to declare his Business, which he said he did in the following

                Speech. </p>

            <p n="20"> Fathers, I am come to tell you your own Speeches; what your own Mouths have

                declared. Fathers, You, in former Days, set a Silver Bason before us, wherein there

                was the Leg of a Beaver, and desir’d of all Nations to come and eat of it ; to eat

                in Peace and Plenty, and not to be churlish to one another ; and that if any such

                Person should be found to be a Disturber, I here lay down by the Edge of the Dish a

                Rod, which you must scourge them with ; and if I your Father, should get foolish, in

                my old Days, I desire you may use it upon me as well as others. </p>

            <p n="21"> Now Fathers, it is you that are the Disturbers in this Land, by coming and

                building your Towns, and taking it away unknown to us, and by Force. </p>

            <p n="22"> Fathers, We kindled a Fire a long Time ago, at a Place called Montreal, where

                we desired you to stay, and not to come and in- trude upon our Land. I now desire

                you may dispatch to that Place ; for be it known to you, Fathers, that this is our

                Land, and not yours </p>

            <p n="23"> Fathers, I desire you may hear me in Civilness ; if not, we must handle that

                Rod which was laid down for the Use of the obstreper- ous. If you had come in a

                peaceable Manner, like our Brothers the English, we should not have been against

                your trading with us, as they do ; but to come, Fathers, and build great Houses upon

                our Land, and to take it by Force, is what we cannot submit to. </p>

            <p n="24"> Fathers, Both you and the English are white, we live in a Country between;

                therefore the Land belongs to neither one nor t’other : But the Great Being above

                allow’d it to be a Place of Res- idence for us ; so Fathers, I desire you to

                withdraw, as I have done our Brothers the English ; for I will keep you at Arms

                length : I lay this down as a Trial for both, to see which will have the great- est

                Regard to it, and that Side we will stand by, and make equal Sharers with us. Our

                Brothers the English have heard this, and I come now to tell it to you, for I am not

                afraid to discharge you off this Land. </p>

            <p n="25"> This he said was the Substance of what he said to the Gen- eral, who made

                this Reply. 15 Miles asunder, and a large Waggon Road between ; they are both built

                after the same Model, but different in the Size ; that on the Lake the largest; he

                gave me a Plan of them, of his own drawing. Now my Child, I have heard your Speech,

                you spoke first, but it is my Time to speak now. Where is my Wampum that you took

                away, with the Marks of Towns in it? This Wampum I do not know, which you have

                discharged me off the Land with ; but you need not put yourself to the Trouble of

                speaking, for I will not hear you : I am not afraid of Flies, or Musquitos, for

                Indians are such as those; I tell you, down that River I will go, and will build

                upon it, according to my Command : If the River was block’d up, I have Forces

                sufficient to burst it open, and tread under my Feet all that stand in Opposition,

                together with their Alliances ; for my Force is as the Sand upon the Sea Shore:

                Therefore, here is your Wampum, I fling it at you. Child, you talk foolish; you say

                this Land belongs to you, but there is not the Black of my Nail yours : I saw that

                Land sooner than you did, before the Shannoahs and you were at War : Lead was the

                Man that went down, and took Pos- session of that River : It is my Land, and I will

                have it, let who will stand up for, or say against it. I’ll buy and sell with the

                Eng- lish, (mockingly). If People will be rul’d by me, they may expect Kindness, but

                not else. </p>

            <p n="26"> The Half-King told me he enquired of the General after two Englishmen that

                were made Prisoners, and received this Answer. hild, You think it is a very great

                Hardship that I made Pris- oners of those two People at Venango, don’t you concern

                yourself with it, we took and carried them to Canada, to get Intelligence of what

                the English were doing in Virginia. He informed me that they had built two Forts,

                one on Lake Erie, and another on French-Creek, near a small Lake about 15 Miles

                asunder, and a large Waggon Road between ; they are both built after the same Model,

                but different in the Size ; that on the Lake the largest; he gave me a Plan of them,

                of his own drawing.</p>

            <p n="27"> The Indians enquired very particularly after their Brothers in Carolina Goal. </p>

            <p n="28"> They also asked what sort of a Boy it was that was taken from the

                South-Branch ; for they had, by some Indians, heard that a Party of French Indians

                had carried a white Boy by the Cuscusca Town, towards the Lakes. 26th. We met in

                Council at the Long-House, about 9 o’Clock, where I spoke to them as

                    follows,<speech>Brothers, I have called you together in Council, by Order of

                    your Brother the Governor of Virginia, to acquaint you that I am sent, with all

                    possible Dispatch, to visit, and deliver a Let- ter to the French Commandant, of

                    very great Importance to your Brothers the English ; and I dare say, to you

                    their Friends and Allies. I was desired, Brothers, by your Brother the Governor,

                    to call upon you, the Sachems of the Nations, to inform you of it, and to ask

                    your Advice and Assistance to proceed the nearest and best Road to the French.

                    You see, Brothers, I have got thus far on my Journey. His Honour likewise

                    desired me to apply to you for some of your young Men, to conduct and provide

                    Provisions for us on our Way, and be a Safeguard against those French Indians

                    who have taken up the Hatchet against us. I have spoke this particularly to you,

                    Brothers, because his Honour our Governor treats you as good Friends and Allies,

                    and holds you in great Esteem. To confirm what I have said, I give you this

                    String of Wampum </speech></p>

            <p n="29"> After they had considered some Time on the above, the Half-King got up and

                    spoke.<speech> Now, my Brothers, in Regard to what my Brother the Governor has

                    desired of me, I return you this Answer. I rely upon you as a Brother ought to

                    do, as you say we are Brothers and one People: We shall put Heart in Hand, and

                    speak to our Fathers the French concerning the Speech they made to me, and you

                    may depend that we will endeavour to be your Guard. Brother, as you have asked

                    my Advice, I hope you will be ruled by it, and stay till I can provide a Company

                    to go with you: The French Speech-Belt is not here, I have it to go for to my

                    hunting Cabbin; likewise the People which I have ordered in, are not yet come,

                    nor cannot till the third Night from this, till which Time, Brother, I must beg

                    you to stay. I intend to send a Guard of Mingo’s, Shannoahs, and Del- awares,

                    that our Brothers may see the Love and Loyalty we bear them.</speech>

            </p>

            <p n="30"> As I had Orders to make all possible Dispatch, and waiting here was very

                contrary to my Inclination, I thanked him in the most suitable Manner I could, and

                told him that my Busi- ness required the greatest Expedition, and would not admit of

                that Delay : He was not well pleased that I should offer to go before the Time he

                had appointed, and told me that he could not consent to our going without a Guard,

                for Fear some Ac- cident should befal us, and draw a Reflection upon him; be- sides,

                says he, this is a Matter of no small Moment, and must not be entered into without

                due Consideration ; for now I in- tend to deliver up the French-Speech-Belt, and

                make the Sha- noahs and Delawares do the same; and accordingly he gave Orders to

                King Shingiss, who was present, to attend on Wednes- day Night with the Wampum, and

                two Men of their Nation to be in Readiness to set out with us next Morning. As I

                found it was impossible to get off without affronting them in the most egregious

                Manner, I consented to stay. </p>

            <p n="31"> I gave them back a String of Wampum that I met with at Mr. Frazier’ s, which

                they had sent with a Speech to his Hon- our the Governor, to inform him, that three

                Nations of French Indians, viz. Chippoways, Ottoways, and Orundacks, had taken up

                the Hatchet against the English, and desired them to repeat it over again, which

                they postponed doing till they met in full Council with the Shannoahs and Delaware

                Chiefs. </p>

            <p n="32">

                <entry> 27th. Runners were dispatched very early for the Shanoah Chiefs, the

                    Half-King set out himself to fetch the French- Speech-Belt from his Hunting

                    Cabbin. </entry>

                <entry> 28th. He returned this Evening, and came with Monoca- toocha, and two other

                    Sachems to my Tent; and begged, (as they had complied with his Honour the

                    Governor’s Request, in providing Men, &amp;c.) to know on what Business we were

                    going to the French? this was a Question I all along expected, and had provided

                    as satisfactory Answers to, as I could, and which allayed their Curiosity a

                    little. </entry>

            </p>

            <p n="33"> Monocatoocha informed me, that an Indian from Venango brought News, a few

                Days ago, that the French had called all the Mingos, Delawares, &amp;c. together at

                that Place, and told them that they intended to have been down the River this Fall,

                but the Waters were growing cold, and the Winter advancing, which obliged them to go

                into Quarters : But they might assur- edly expect them in the Spring, with a far

                greater Number; and desired that they might be quite passive, and not to inter-

                meddle, unless they had a Mind to draw all their Force upon them, for that they

                expected to fight the English three Years, (as they supposed there would be some

                Attempts made to stop them) in which Time they should conquer, but if they should

                prove equally strong, that they and the English, would join to cut them all off, and

                divide the Land between them ; that tho’ they had lost their General, and some few

                of their Soldiers, yet there were Men enough to reinforce them, and make them

                Masters of the Ohio. </p>

            <p n="34"> This Speech, he said, was delivered to them by one Captain Joncaire their

                Interpreter in Chief, living at Venango, and a Man of Note in the Army.<entry>29th.

                    The Half-King and Monocatoocha, came very early, and begged me to stay one Day

                    more, for notwithstanding they had used all the Diligence in their Power, the

                    Shanoah Chiefs had not brought the Wampum they ordered, but would

                    certainlybeinTo-night;ifnot,theywoulddelaymenolon- ger, but would send it after

                    us as soon as they arrived : When I found them so pressing in their Request, and

                    knew that return- ing of Wampum was the abolishing of Agreements; and giv- ing

                    this up, was shaking of all Dependence upon the French, I consented to stay, as

                    I believed an Offence offered at this Cri- sis, might be attended with greater

                    ill Consequence, than an- other Day’s Delay. They also informed me that Shingiss

                    could not get in his Men, and was prevented from coming himself by his Wife’s

                    Sickness, (I believe, by Fear of the French ) but that the Wampum of that Nation

                    was lodged with Custaloga one of their Chiefs at Venango. In the Evening late

                    they came again and acquainted me that the Shannoahs were not yet come, but it

                    should not retard the Prosecution of our Journey. He delivered in my Hearing,

                    the Speeches that were to be made to the French, by Jeskakake, one of their old

                    Chiefs, which was giving up the Belt the late Com- mandant had asked for, and

                    repeating near the same Speech he himself had done before. He also delivered a

                    String of Wampum to this Chief, which was sent by King Shingiss, to be given to

                    Custaloga, with Or- ders to repair to the French, and deliver up the Wampum.He

                    likewise gave a very large String of black and white Wampum, which was to be

                    sent up immediately to the Six Na- tions, if the French refused to quit the Land

                    at this Warning ; which was the third and last Time, and was the Right of this

                    Jeskakake to deliver.</entry>

                <entry> 30th. Last Night the great Men assembled to their Council- House, to consult

                    further about this Journey, and who were to go ; the Result of which was, that

                    only three of their Chiefs, with one of their best Hunters, should be our

                    Convoy: The Reason which they gave for not sending more, after what had been

                    proposed at Council the 26th, was, that a greater Num- ber might give the French

                    Suspicions of some bad Design, and cause them to be treated rudely: But I rather

                    think they could not get their Hunters in.We set out about 9 o’Clock with the

                    Half-King, Jeskakake, White Thunder, and the Hunter, and travelled on the Road

                    to Venango, where we arrived the 4th of December, without any Thing remarkable

                    happening but a continued Series of bad Weather. This is an old Indian Town,

                    situated at the Mouth of French Creek on Ohio, and lies near N. about 60 Miles

                    from the Loggs-Town, but more than 70 the Way we were obliged to go.We found the

                    French Colours hoisted at a House which they drove Mr. John Frazier, an English

                    Subject, from ; I im- mediately repaired to it, to know where the Commander re-

                    sided: There were three Officers, one of whom, Capt. Jon- caire, inform’d me,

                    that he had the Command of the Ohio, but that there was a General Officer at the

                    near Fort, which he ad- vised me to for an Answer. He invited us to sup with

                    them, and treated us with the greatest Complaisance.The Wine, as they dosed

                    themselves pretty plentifully with it, soon banished the Restraint which at

                    first appear’d in their Conversation, and gave a License to their Tongues to

                    reveal their Sentiments more freely.They told me, That it was their absolute

                    Design to take Possession of the Ohio, and by G— they would do it ; for that

                    they were sensible the English could raise two Men for their one ; yet they

                    knew, their Motions were too slow and dilatory to prevent any Undertaking of

                    theirs. They pretend to have an</entry>

            </p>





        </body>





    </div>











</root>

